Conor W. Hanson

Coon Rapids, MN 608-219-5058 | condorhanson@gmail.com LinkedIn | Portfolio | GitHub

Summary

I am a Data and Information Systems Coordinator in the field of Program Evaluation & Research. From data system design, data processing and cleaning, to analysis and visualization, I have a wide array of experience in data analysis.

I work primarily in Python leveraging libraries such as Pandas and Numpy, as well as utilizing APIs to build data ETL pipelines. I have experience in PostgreSQL and NoSQL database design and maintenance using SQLAlchemy and PGAdmin. I also possess advanced Excel, Google Sheets, and Smartsheet skills. I have experience setting up BI and interactive dashboards on Tableau, Dash, and Plotly and ensure all my deliverables are designed with detail and care toward the stated goals of stakeholders.

I enjoy a good technical challenge and am a fast learner, always reading up on and experimenting with the latest data science tools and processes. I possess strong analytical skills, critical thinking skills, and communication skills, both written and verbal. I enjoy working with a team, I take direction well, and delight in well-written code and compelling data visualizations that support business and stakeholder goals.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages:

Python
SQL
R
JavaScript
HTML
VBA
Google Apps Script

Softwares/Platforms:

Microsoft Office (Word, Excel)

Google Workspace (Docs, Sheets, Admin)

Python Packages: Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly, Numpy, Flask, SQLAlchemy Big Data processing in PySpark GitHub version control APIs with Python and JavaScript Natural Language Processing (NLP) Tableau Smartsheet RStudio VSCode AWS S3 and RDS

Education

Data Analysis & Visualization BootCamp Certificate: University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN *March 2022 - September 2022*

This was a 24-week intensive bootcamp designed to immerse us in the world and tools of data science. It was heavily focused on data analysis and processing in Python, but included the necessary training with R, SQL and non-relational databases, Big Data storage and processing, ETL development, web app construction, and a good dose of machine learning and neural networks.

B.A. in Philosophy (summa cum laude): University of Wisconsin - Stevens Point, Stevens Point, WI 2015 - 2019

Areas of interest/competency: Philosophy of Religion, Philosophical Theology, Christian Theology, Moral Philosophy, Ethics, Metaphysics, Political Philosophy/Political Theory, Logic.

Awards: Continuing Student Scholarship - Department of Philosophy, Spring 2018

Distinguished Achievement Award, Continuing Student in the Department of Philosophy - College of Letters and Sciences, Spring 2018

Boethius Book Award, Spring 2019

Publications: "How Dave Chappelle and Saint Augustine Help Us See Ourselves" in *Dave Chappelle and Philosophy: When Keeping It Wrong Gets Real (Pop Culture and Philosophy)* Ed. Mark Ralkowski. Chicago: Open Universe, 2021.

2-Year Technical Diploma Automotive Technician: Madison Area Technical College 2008-2010

Experience

Data and Information Systems Coordinator - ACET, Inc. Bloomington, MN

September 2023 - present

I research, test, recommend, and develop data and information systems pertinent to internal company and client process and organizational improvements. I harness many APIs and build data pipelines using Python to automate company processes and client project data needs, spearhead development and implementation of internal company data security systems and policies, and maintain company software platforms such as Google Workspace and Smartsheet.

Research and Data Assistant - ACET, Inc. Bloomington, MN

September 2022 - September 2023

I obtained and organized literature/data for review, administered surveys and supported data collection efforts, took and summarized notes at internal and client meetings, organized and co-facilitated focus groups and interviews, recorded and reviewed data for quality, transferred data into spreadsheets, tables, and charts to illustrate key findings, explored, cleaned, and analyzed data, tracked data and supported project teams.

Stay-at-home-dad

September 2021 - September 2022

I have been the primary caretaker for my daughter since her birth in 2019, but I've stayed home full-time with her since September 2021. It was during this time I began my Data Analysis program at the U of M.